Matthew Lui

mattclui@gmail.com • Irvine, CA * mattclui.github.io * mattlui

PROFILE

I am a full-stack software engineer based in Irvine, California. After working for over a decade in investment management, I decided to invest in myself and pursue my passion for problem solving through programming. Most recently I co-created Snowclone, an open source backend-as-a-service supporting realtime applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer and Co-Creator, Snowclone *∂*

Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

Snowclone is an open-source backend-as-a-service that streamlines the process of provisioning and managing cloud infrastructure for the deployment of realtime-enabled web applications.

- Designed a service to launch a Postgres database, a schema-uploading UI, a REST API, and a realtime notifications server with a single command (Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, PostgREST, SSE, Docker)
- Architected a solution to deploy Snowclone on AWS within minutes, leveraging Terraform to configure and provision the 50+ necessary resources (AWS: ECS Fargate, RDS, Elastic Load Balancer; Terraform)
- Built a CLI to facilitate the deployment and removal of backends, condensing dozens of configuration steps into six simple commands (AWS: S3, DynamoDB; Node.js)
- · Authored an in-depth technical case study documenting the problem domain and design decisions
- Collaborated with a team of four remote engineers using agile workflow (Slack, Github)

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

2022 – 2024 | Irvine, CA

Developed freelance open-source applications including:

- Rekwestbin A tool for collecting and inspecting webhooks (DO, Nginx, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, EJS)
- Prayer Partner An app for recording and tracking prayer requests (Node.js, Express, MongoDB)

Vice President, Investment Research, Canterbury Consulting

2018 - 2022 | Newport Beach, CA

- · Chaired the global equity research team, developing manager selection and portfolio construction strategies
- Oversaw \$10B+ in public equity and alternative investments for individuals, endowments, and foundations
- Managed over 70 relationships with investment firms and negotiated fee savings of \$1,400,000 on behalf of clients

EDUCATION

Launch School, 2022 – 2024

Software Engineering and Full-Stack Development $\, \varnothing \,$

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum

University of California, Berkeley, Bachelor of Arts, Economics

2004 – 2007 | Berkeley, CA

SKILLS

Backend	Frontend	Cloud	Other
Node.js, Express, Go,	JavaScript, React,	DigitalOcean, AWS,	Git/Github, Docker,
PostgreSQL,	Handlebars,	Terraform, Render	HTTP, WebSockets,
MongoDB, REST APIs	HTML/CSS		Jest, OOP, Nginx,
			Postman